Color is an important tool in designing visualizations.
颜色是可视化设计中的一个重要工具
It allows you to encode another variable or split your data into groups.
你可以用颜色编码另一个变量或把数据分组
However, there are a lot of issues you need to
然而 你需要考虑很多问题
consider when choosing which colors to use and how to apply them.
比如选择使用哪些颜色以及如何使用它们
As an example of the power of color,
为了说明颜色的强大之处
consider these two plots of GDP versus life expectancy.
我们来看一下这两张关于 GDP 和预期寿命之间关系的图
Look how much more information adding color provided.
看一看增加颜色后 如何使传达的信息变多
We got the idea that higher GDPs correlate with higher life expectancy, however,
我们可以看到 GDP 和寿命之间是正相关的
by adding color, the region of the countries belong to is now more apparent.
添加颜色后 国家对应的地区在图上变得更加明显
We can see how the countries are distributed in the world in this plot.
从这张图里 我们能够看到世界上各个国家
The low GDP countries are almost all in sub-saharan Africa.
几乎所有低 GDP 国家都位于非洲撒哈拉以南地区
And on the high end,
而在高 GDP 的一边
you see Europe and North America.
你可以看到欧洲和北美
The orange in between is the former Soviet states.
位于两者之间的橙色为前苏联国家
Color is an important tool in visualizations,
颜色是可视化的一项重要工具
and it's important to use it appropriately to have the largest impact.
恰当地使用它 能够极大地提升效果
Consider this bar chart.
来看一下这个反面例子
Overall, I would say that color distracts from the data.
总体而言 我觉得 这里的颜色让人分心
The colors shown don't appear to be chosen for any particular reason.
这里的颜色似乎是随意选择的 没有任何原因
In fact, they're are actually the default for
事实上 这些颜色是软件
the software in which this plot was built, rainbow colors.
在生成该图时的默认颜色 即彩虹色
These colors are also quite bright which strains the eyes.
这些颜色也非常鲜艳 有点刺眼
Above all, each color doesn't actually convey any additional information about the data.
事实上 每个颜色也并没有传递任何关于数据的额外信息
The labels on the left side of the bar plot are enough to
柱状图左侧的标签其实就已足够显示
indicate which bar belongs to which type of diamonds cut.
哪一个条形属于哪一类钻石切割
This actually makes the use of color redundant since
这使得颜色的使用非常多余
both the labels and the color are indicating the cut type.
因为标签和颜色都表示了 CUT 变量
You might also have noticed that the legend at the right is unnecessary.
你或许也注意到了右侧的图例并没有必要
We could simply design this visualization with the labels at the left of the graph,
使用图形左侧的这些标签其实就够了
decreasing the amount of time
这样可以减少读者的阅读时间
the reader's eye jump between the legend and the main data display.
不用在图例和图表主体之间来回切换
Here are my three main tips for using color and plot.
关于颜色在图表中的使用 我有三个主要建议
My first piece of advice comes from the design field.
我的第一个建议来自于设计领域
Get it right in black and white.
首选黑白色系
Before you begin adding color to your data visualization,
给数据可视化添加颜色之前
you should determine if you need color in the first place.
首先要确定是否有必要添加颜色
Many times, black, white and shades of
许多情况下 黑色、白色以及灰色阴影
grey will be enough to effectively convey your information.
足以有效地传递你的信息
Secondly, if you are going to use color,
第二 如果你打算使用颜色
consider using less intense colors such as natural colors or pastels.
尽量使用不那么鲜艳的颜色 例如天然色或淡色
You can also add some gray value to bright colors to make them less vibrant.
你也可以在鲜艳的颜色中加入灰色 使颜色看起来更柔和
Colors with higher gray values have
灰度值高的颜色
a softer feel and the eye can concentrate on them for longer periods of time.
给人感觉更柔和 眼睛能更长时间地看这些颜色
Rainbow colors, primary colors and
彩虹色、原色以及
other bright bold colors create noisy visualizations that strain the eye.
其他鲜艳的亮色給可视化增加了噪点 并且还刺激眼睛
My final tip is to make color selections that facilitate communication.
最后 我建议颜色的选择要有助于信息的传播
In this example, I used a complimentary color to
在前面的示例里 我使用了互补色
draw attention to the count of ideal cut diamonds.
使读者注意理想的钻石切割数
You could use a similar strategy if you
如果你想在一个图表中突出特定的数据点
want to highlight particular data points in a graphic.
你也可以采用类似的策略
Perhaps you've come across
你可能已经遇到过
some good and not so good examples of color use in visualizations.
可视化中一些有关颜色使用的好案例或不太好的案例
Color can be a tricky component of a visualization but can also encode data,
颜色是可视化中一个比较棘手的元素
lead the eye, and help viewers see the most important information of a graphic.
用得好将有助于引导读者的注意力以及传递最重要的信息